Welcome back to Apush in under 3
minutes. No time for intros, let's get
into it. So, this African-American Civil
Rights Movement has gotten really big by
the '60s. So, the big idea here is all
these other groups of minorities are
seeing the success of this big movement
and are getting inspired to do something
similar with their group. We have five
groups to go over in this video, so
let's get into it. Latinos will start
the Chicano Movement where leaders like
Cesar Chavez will form the United Farm
Workers to fight low wages and poor
working conditions. An example of things
they did were non- violent things such
as a national consumer boycott of
California table grapes. This would lead
to union contracts, better wages, and
safer working conditions. Moving on
though, American Indians formed their
own movement as well. The goal here was
to reclaim their own rights and protest
government treatment. The two big things
that happened here were that Native
American groups would forcibly occupy
the prison Alcatraz and the town of
Wounded Knee in an effort to protest the
federal government. But now let's move
over to Asian Americans. This one was
more focused on giving Asians their own
identity in America. And lots of what
you see here are college protests
against anti-Asian racism. Now let's
move over to feminism. If you remember
in the past, we had our era of first
wave feminism. Now we are in the
technical second wave where women are
going to advocate for full equal rights
such as equal pay, workplace equality,
and an equal rights amendment. An
organization here popularized was the
National Organization for Women or NOW.
And a really important book made here
was Betty Friedan's The Feminine exposed
the lack of fulfillment an American
housewife truly has. And finally, the
LGBTQ+ community had their own movement
as well to try and fight discrimination
and demand recognition. A key turning
point in this movement was the Stonewall
Riots which would eventually lead to a
later gay liberation movement. That's
all for this topic. On the screen now
are AP style questions for this topic.
Pause now.
I'll put the answers on the screen now.
I will see you in the next one.